Okay, before we made a sling using the double fisherman's knot.
This is a sling that I use.
It is kind of a longer sling, but I use this for a backing up belay device such as like an ATC, or Traffic Control, or a figure eight.
I will show you how to use that later.
But anyway, first thing you need to know about your sling is a way to carry it around that is useful.
A lot of guys will throw it over like so.
This kind of bothers me just because it is just something that could get stuck.
What I actually like to do is start at the bottom and kind of fold it in half.
I am going to leave enough room because we are going to wrap the other end around this.
And you just start wrapping like so.
You just keep going around till you get to the end.
Then you have this loop on here that is created from the rope that we just wrapped around and pass the loop from the rope that you were wrapping and then you can tighten it up here.
This gives you a nice little hook or a loop to hook through with a Caribbean or whatnot.
It is not the best to store because if you store a rope and you are going to put weight on it, it is not the best idea to have because it starts to break down the fibers.